<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A few proposals offered in humility and in the spirit of meekness, to the supreme authority, the Parliament of the Commonwealth of England. Holding forth a medium or essay for the removing of tythes, and establishing a maintenance for a godly ministry in the nation: such as may be satisfying to the consciences of all sober-minded men, and injurious to no mans just propriety or interest. Which were some time since presented to the Parliament, by several well-affected people in the county of Suffolk; and now published by a well-wisher to England's peace, and the Gospel's prosperity.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1659</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A85248</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F835</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E993_29</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R207789</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99866818</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99866818</idno>
            <idno type="VID">119104</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A85248)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 119104)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 148:E993[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A few proposals offered in humility and in the spirit of meekness, to the supreme authority, the Parliament of the Commonwealth of England. Holding forth a medium or essay for the removing of tythes, and establishing a maintenance for a godly ministry in the nation: such as may be satisfying to the consciences of all sober-minded men, and injurious to no mans just propriety or interest. Which were some time since presented to the Parliament, by several well-affected people in the county of Suffolk; and now published by a well-wisher to England's peace, and the Gospel's prosperity.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 5, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for L. Chapman, at the Crown in Peopes-head-Alley,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1659.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Aug 20".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tithes --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:119104:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A Few PROPOSALS Offered In humility and in the ſpirit of meek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, to the Supreme Authority, the Parliament of the Commonwealth of ENGLAND.</p>
            <p>Holding forth A MEDIUM or ESSAY FOR The Removing of TYTHES, and eſtabliſhing a Maintenance for A Godly Miniſtry in the Nation: Such as may be ſatisfying to the Conſciences of all Sober-minded Men, and injurious to no Mans juſt Propriety or Intereſt.</p>
            <p>Which were ſome time ſince preſented to the Parliament, by ſeveral well-affected People in the County of Suffolk;</p>
            <p>And now publiſhed By a Well-wiſher to England's Peace, and the Goſpels Proſperity.</p>
            <p>London, Printed for L. Chapman, at the Crown in Popes-head-Alley. 1659.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="list_of_proposals">
            <pb facs="tcp:119104:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:119104:2"/>
            <list>
               <head>A Few PROPOSALS Offered In Humility and in the Spirit of Meekneſs, TO THE Supreme Authority, the Parliament OF The COMMONWEALTH of ENGLAND.</head>
               <item>1. THat all the Tythes within this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth, be expoſed to ſale at ſo many years purchaſe, as in the wiſdom of the Parliament ſhall be thought
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:119104:3"/>meet; that ſo every man may by buying in his own Tythes, free his Eſtate from that En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumbrance: and in caſe any ſhall refuſe to purchaſe his own Tythes, liberty be given for any other man to buy them.</item>
               <item>2. That all Glebe-Lands, Parſonage-Houſes, Deans and Chapters lands, and all other Revenues whatſoever belonging to the Miniſtry, be ſold, except ſuch onely where a preaching Miniſter is to be ſettled.</item>
               <item>3. That a ſurvey be taken of the number and conveniency of all the publick meeting-places or Churches in this Commonwealth, that ſo ſupernumeraries may be aboliſhed; and where there is a deficiency, ſupply may be made according to a rule of proportion in that caſe to be provided.</item>
               <item>4. That with the Monies ariſing out of the ſaid Sales, Lands may be purchaſed in or near every ſuch Town where a preaching Miniſter is to be ſettled; which together with the Glebes and other Lands and Revenues
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:119104:3"/>before reſerved for that end, may make up a competent maintenance for every ſuch Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter; as ſuppoſe 80 l. per annum for every Miniſter in the Country, and 100 li. per annum for the Miniſter in every Market-Town.</item>
               <item>5. That theſe Lands ſo Purchaſed and ſet apart by Authority for the Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of the Miniſtry, may be in the poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, and at the diſpoſe of every ſuch Miniſter, to be by him improved to the beſt Advantage for the maintenance of him and his Family, and not brought into a publick Treaſury.</item>
               <item>6. That in caſe there ſhall be a redundancy or over-plus by the Sales of the former, more then will pay the purchaſe of the later, (as it is humbly conceived there may be) the ſame may be put into a publick Treaſury, and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved (the ſtock and principal being al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways preſerved) for the relief of ſuch Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters as may poſſibly by this alteration be laid aſide, and have no other way of Lively<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood;
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:119104:4"/>and alſo for the Widows and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phans of ſuch Miniſters as may without their Sin, and abuſe of Mercy, be left in a Poor and Neceſſitous Condition; that ſo good Miniſters may be delivered from the Fear, and their Wives and Children from the Reproach and Miſery of unavoydable Poverty.</item>
               <item>7. That in caſe there ſhould not be ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient by the Sales of the one, to diſcharge and pay for the purchaſe of the other, a vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luntary Contribution be made by all per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons within this Commonwealth, who are well-affected to ſo good a work; that ſo the defect may be ſupplyed, and the redundan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy (if any be) employed to the aforeſaid ends.</item>
               <item>8. Laſtly, that perſons of known fidelity, and good affection to the work, be employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the management of this Affair, and a convenient ſpace of time given wherein the ſame may be effected, and a ſet time fixed for the receiving and paying of all ſuch Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:119104:4"/>as ſhall be due either to or from the State upon ſuch Contracts: that ſo at one and the ſame time the one may be removed, and the other introduced, and all inconvenien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces avoided, which otherwiſe might happen by fraud and delay in ſuch Tranſactions.</item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
